A Guide to the Michael Two Horses Collection, undated
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Michael Two Horses Collection, undated
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2006-001
2.8 cu. ft. 2 boxes
The collection contains a combination of academic papers, personal papers and research, drawings, correspondence, thesis and dissertation materials, and some artifacts from Two Horses' career as a student, scholar, and activist.
Two Horses, Michael
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Michael Two Horses Collection was donated to Special Collections in August 2005.
Biographical Note
Michael Two Horses was a scholar, researcher, and activist. From the fall of 2003 until the time of his death in late December 2003, he was a visiting instructor in the American Indian Studies Program and the Humanities Program, within the Department of Interdisciplinary Studies. He was also a member of the Virginia Tech Commission on Equal Opportunity and Diversity. More biographical information is available in his obituary online.
Scope and Content
The collection contains a combination of academic papers, personal papers and research, drawings, correspondence, thesis and dissertation materials, and some artifacts from Two Horses' career as a student, scholar, and activist.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in folder by subject/materials type. Folders are in alphabetical order.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Faculty; University Archives; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- Aboriginal Organizations and Services, British Columbia, 1999 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Animal Liberation Primer (Box-folder 1-2)
- Arizona Territory Gourd Society, INC. (Box-folder 1-3)
- Artwork (Box-folder 1-4)
- Beadwork (Box-folder 1-5)
- Bibliographies, American Indian Studies (Box-folder 1-6)
- Caucasian American Workbook (Box-folder 1-7)
- Chinook Washington State University Yearbook, 1996 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Columbus- Teacher Resources (Box-folder 1-9)
- Day Calendar, 2002 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Dissertation Proposal (Box-folder 1-11)
- Indian School Days (Box-folder 1-12)
- Emails (Box-folder 1-13)
- "Drumming Up Resistance: The Anti-Indian Movement in Montana" (Box-folder 1-14)
- Financial Aid (Box-folder 1-15)
- Grade Reports/Transcripts (Box-folder 1-16)
- Handwritten Notes (Box-folder 1-17)
- "Hitchita!"- Greg Sevier Homicide, 1992 (Box-folder 1-18)
- Indian Mascots (Box-folder 1-19)
- Indian Hating (Box-folder 1-20)
- Indian Identity (Box-folder 1-21)
- Lakota Ceremonial Songs (Box-folder 1-22)
- Lakota Language- 1 (Box-folder 1-23)
- Lakota Language- 2 (Box-folder 1-24)
- Law School (Box-folder 1-25)
- Letters- Academic (Box-folder 1-26)
- Letters- Personal (Box-folder 1-27)
- "Little White People- A Rhyme" (Box-folder 1-28)
- Journal (Box-folder 1-29)
- Makah Indians- 2 (Box-folder 1-31)
- Makah- 1 (Box-folder 1-32)
- Makah- 2 (Box-folder 1-33)
- Makah Whaling Questionnaire- 1 (Box-folder 1-34)
- Makah Whaling Questionnaire- 2 (Box-folder 1-35)
- Makah Whaling Questionnaire- 3 (Box-folder 1-36)
- Masters Degree Study Plan- Two Horses (Box-folder 2-1)
- Memorial Song (Box-folder 2-2)
- Military Patches (Box-folder 2-3)
- Navajo(Dine) (Box-folder 2-4)
- Newspaper Articles (Box-folder 2-5)
- Pacific Northwest Quarterly, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 2-6)
- Peltier, Leonard, 1978-1993 (Box-folder 2-7)
- Personnel Forms (Box-folder 2-8)
- Photographs (Box-folder 2-9)
- Poetry (Box-folder 2-10)
- Pow Wows (Box-folder 2-11)
- Presentations (Box-folder 2-12)
- Receipts (Box-folder 2-13)
- Sea Shepherd Conservation Society- 1 (Box-folder 2-14)
- Sea Shepherd Conservation Society- 2 (Box-folder 2-15)
- Syllabi (Box-folder 2-16)
- Taxes (Box-folder 2-17)
- Teaching Evaluations (Box-folder 2-18)
- Thesis- General (Box-folder 2-19)
- Thesis- Chapters 1-5 (Box-folder 2-20)
- Thesis- Chapters 6-Bibliography (Box-folder 2-21)
- Tieri, Mike- Class Papers (Box-folder 2-22)
- Tieri, Mike- Class Papers 2 (Box-folder 2-23)
- Tieri, Mike- Oral Interview (Box-folder 2-24)
- Tipis, Indian (Box-folder 2-25)
- Treaties, Indian (Box-folder 2-26)
- Tribal Directory, 1999 (Box-folder 2-27)
- Two Horses, Mike Class Papers (Box-folder 2-28)
- Two Horses/ Tieri Personal Papers (Box-folder 2-29)
- Vitae (Box-folder 2-30)
- Washington Tribes and Reservations (Box-folder 2-31)
- "We Know Who The Real Indians Are" Two Horses, Michael (Box-folder 2-32)
- Weapons- Indian (Box-folder 2-33)
- Western Shoshoni Dictionary Project (Box-folder 2-34)
- Wounded Knee (Box-folder 2-35)
- Writing Samples (Box-folder 2-36)